Finding Aid for University of Michigan. Dept. of Medicine and Surgery Theses, 1851-1878
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Dept. of Medicine and Surgery (University of Michigan) theses 1851-1878
University of Michigan. Dept. of Medicine and Surgery.
57 rolls of microfilm: 1449 theses
Theses written by University of Michigan Medical School students; subjects concern the theory and treatment of specific diseases, as well as the psychology of medicine, attitudes toward women and child rearing, the social standing of the physician, and medical practices during the mid-nineteenth century.
87223 Bimu C53 2
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The theses were transferred to the Michigan Historical Collections in 1939 by the University of Michigan Medical School, Donor No. 647.
The collection is open for research. The microfilm is available through inter-library loan.
The original theses are available for use in the library.
The University of Michigan was the first state university to operate a medical school. Medicine was the second oldest field of study there, after classics. The program was started in 1850, and at that time the course lasted only a few months.
In a letter dated October 10, 1938, a proposal to form a Medical School collection as part of the Michigan Historical Collections was submitted to Dr. A. C. Furstenberg, Dean of the Medical School. He replied in December that the executive committee of the Medical School did indeed favor the transfer of records to the university archives. This transfer was made in early 1939.
Among the records transferred were medical theses written by students during the years 1851-1878 (the requirement was dropped in the latter year). Those for 1851-1862 were formerly bound in compilation volumes, one or more for each year, but have been disbound, due to the deterioration of the bindings, so as to be filed in separate folders. The theses for 1863-1878 were individually bound. Most of the theses were based on lectures, medical books, and/or periodicals, but some were based on personal experience, as many of the students had practiced medicine before entering medical school, some as surgeons during the Civil War.
The medical theses are arranged by year of graduation, then alphabetically by student name.
Summary Contents List
Roll 1
1851-1852
1853 [Arnold through Carpender]
Roll 2
Theses 1853 [Carpenter through end]
Theses 1854 [Bailey through Herrick]
Roll 3
Theses 1854 [Howland through end]
Theses 1855 [Baker through Hazen]
Roll 4
Theses 1855 [Hendee through end]
Theses 1856 [Baird through Winne]
Roll 5
Thesis, 1856 [Witter]
Theses 1857
Theses 1858 [Anderson through Hosack]
Roll 6
Theses 1858 [Leach through end]
Theses 1859 [Breakey through Randolph]
Roll 7
Theses 1859 [Raymond through end]
Theses 1860 [Bowen through Hesse]
Roll 8
Theses 1860 [Lord through end]
Theses 1861 [Allen through Curtis]
Roll 9
Theses 1861 [Emerson through Tweedale]
Roll 10
Theses 1861 [Whittemore through end]
Theses 1862 [Brockett through Sweetland]
Roll 11
Theses 1862 [Thacker through end]
Theses 1863 [Baker through Ranney]
Roll 12
Theses 1863 [Rice through end]
Theses 1864 [Anderson through Ling]
Roll 13
Theses 1864 [Lund through end]
Theses Thesis, 1865 [Ames]
Roll 14
Theses 1865 [Andrews through Hicks]
Roll 15
Theses 1865 [Jackson through Whitman]
Roll 16
Theses 1865 [Wiley through end]
Theses 1866 Armstrong through Jenkins]
Roll 17
Theses 1866 [Jennings through Robbins]
Roll 18
Theses 1866 [Robinson through end]
Theses 1867 [Allen through Chavey]
Roll 19
Theses 1867 [Cheever through Hotchkiss]
Roll 20
Theses 1867 [Hurd through Read]
Roll 21
Theses 1867 [Revenaugh through Stickel]
Roll 22
Theses 1867 [Thompson through end]
Theses 1868 [Adams through Corey]
Roll 23
Theses 1868 [Cox through Kirk]
Roll 24
Theses 1868 [Knapp through Scovill]
Roll 25
Theses 1868 [Shaw through end]
Theses 1869 [Ambrose through Bloomfield]
Roll 26
Theses 1869 [Boise through Cole]
Roll 27
Theses 1869 [Creagh through Hagle]
Roll 28
Theses 1869 [Hamilton through Matthews]
Roll 29
Theses 1869 [Merrill through Pratt]
Roll 30
Theses 1869 [Priest through Thorp]
Roll 31
Theses 1869 [Tindall through end]
Theses 1870 [Adair through Canedy]
Roll 32
Theses 1870 [Case through Hamilton]
Roll 33
Theses 1870 [Harding through Matheson]
Roll 34
Theses 1870 [Maxson through Wight]
Roll 35
Theses 1870 [Wilder through end]
Theses 1871 [Abbott through A. Campbell]
Roll 36
Theses 1871 [M. Campbell through Downie]
Roll 37
Theses 1871 [Duncan through Hunt]
Roll 38
Theses 1871 [Johnson through Rockwell]
Roll 39
Theses 1871 [Root through end]
Theses Thesis, 1872 [Adams]
Roll 40
Theses 1872 [Anderson through Green]
Roll 41
Theses 1872 [Harris through Lundy]
Roll 42
Theses 1872 [McCormick through Phelps]
Roll 43
Theses 1872 [Ranney through end]
Theses Thesis, 1873 [Aitcheson]
Roll 44
Theses 1873 [Atwood through Fullerton]
Roll 45
Theses 1873 [Gandy through McGregor]
Roll 46
Theses 1873 [McGrew through Smith]
Roll 47
Theses 1873 [Snook through end]
Theses 1874 [Barrett through Bordner]
Roll 48
Theses 1874 [Broucher through McCarty]
Roll 49
Theses 1874 [McCaslin through A. Taylor]
Roll 50
Theses 1874 [O. Taylor through end]
Theses 1875 [Alleman through Gerow]
Roll 51
Theses 1875 [Gleason through McCallum]
Roll 52
Theses 1875 [McCandless through Thomson]
Roll 53
Theses 1875 [Tremper through end]
Theses 1876 [Anderson through Connor]
Roll 54
Theses 1876 [Cosens through Luscomb]
Roll 55
Theses 1876 [McDonald through West]
Roll 56
Theses 1876 [White through end]
Theses 1877 [Allyn through Howell]
Roll 57
Theses 1877 [Ingram through end]
Theses 1878
Theses Undated
Theses written by University of Michigan Medical School students; subjects concern the theory and treatment of specific diseases, as well as the psychology of medicine, attitudes toward women and child rearing, the social standing of the physician, and medical practices during the mid-nineteenth century.
Subjects:
Abortion.; Aconite.; Air.; Alcohol.; Alcoholism.; Allergy.; Amenorrhea.; Amyl Nitrite.; Anatomy.; Anatomy, Comparative.; Anemia.; Anesthesia.; Anthropology.; Antiseptics.; Arsenic.; Arthritis.; Aspirin.; Asthma.; Belladonna (Drug); Biochemistry.; Blood--Circulation.; Blood pressure.; Blood--Transfusion.; Phlebotomy.; Bones.; Brain.; Brant County (Ont.); Bromides.; Bronchitis.; Brucellosis.; Cancer.; Carbolic acid.; Cass County (Mich.); Cataract.; Cells.; Cerebrovascular disease.; Clinical chemistry.; Pharmaceutical chemistry.; Childbirth.; Children--Health and hygiene.; Chloral.; Chloroform.; Circumcision.; Colitis.; Communicable diseases.; Convulsions.; Croup.; Cysts (Pathology); Death.; Diabetes.; Diagnosis.; Diagnosis, Laboratory.; Diarrhea.; Diarrhea, Infantile.; Digestion.; Diphtheria.; Disinfection and disinfectants.; Dislocations.; Dreams.; Drugs.; Dynamics.; Dysentery.; Indigestion.; Edema.; Electricity.; Electrotherapeutics.; Embolism.; Embryology.; Emetics.; Emphysema, Pulmonary.; Endocarditis.; Epidemics.; Epilepsy.; Epithelium.; Erysipelas.; Ether.; Evolution.; Eye.; Fever.; Food.; Fractures.; Galen.; Gangrene.; Garrod, Alfred Baring, Sir, 1819-1907.; Germ theory of disease.; Glycerin.; Goiter.; Gonorrhea.; Gunshot wounds.; Gunn, Moses, 1822-1887.; Hahnemann, Samuel, 1755-1843.; Hand.; Cleft lip.; Headache.; Heart.; Heat.; Heatstroke.; Hemorrhage.; Hernia.; Hippocrates.; Histology.; Homeopathy.; Hygiene.; Hygiene, Sexual.; Hysteria.; Immunity.; Inflammation.; Insanity.; Insomnia.; Iodine.; Kalamazoo (Mich.); Kidneys.; Kidneys--Diseases.; Lead poisoning.; Leukemia.; Life (Biology); Light.; Lind, James, 1716-1794.; Liver.; Lungs.; Lymphatics.; Malaria.; Marijuana.; Masturbation.; Measles.; Medical instruments and apparatus.; Medical jurisprudence.; Medicine.; Medicine--History.; Medicine, Military.; Medicine, Psychosomatic.; Medicine--Study and teaching.; Meningitis.; Menstruation.; Mental health.; Mercury.; Metabolism.; Miasma.; Microscopes.; Microscopy.; Mucous membrane.; Muscles.; Narcotics.; Nervous system.; Neuralgia.; Nutrition.; Ophthalmology.; Opium.; Ovaries.; Pain.; Pancreas.; Paralysis.; Pathology.; Pediatrics.; Peritonitis.; Phlebitis.; Physical diagnosis.; Physicians.; Physiology.; Pleurisy.; Pneumonia.; Poisons.; Poliomyelitis.; Poultices.; Pregnancy.; Prostate.; Psychology, Pathological.; Public health.; Puerperal septicemia.; Laxatives.; Quarantine.; Quinine.; Rabies.; Reproduction.; Respiration.; Rheumatism.; Rickets.; Sanitation.; Scarlatina.; Scrotum.; Scurvy.; Sense-organs.; Septicemia.; Sexually transmitted diseases.; Skin.; Sleep.; Smallpox.; Spermatorrhea.; Spine.; Spleen.; Spontaneous generation.; Stomach--Ulcers.; Surgery.; Syphilis.; Teeth.; Tetanus.; Therapeutics.; Thrombosis.; Tobacco.; Tongue.; Tonsillitis.; Toxicology.; Trachoma.; Trephining.; Trichinosis.; Tuberculosis.; Typhoid Fever.; Typhus Fever.; Ulcers.; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Medical care.; University of Michigan. Dept. of Medicine and Surgery.; Urea.; Uremia.; Urinary organs.; Uterus.; Vaccination.; Ventilation.; Veratrine.; Vitamins.; Water.; Women--Health and hygiene.; Yellow fever.
- Medical Theses
  - Class of 1851
    - Alexander, J. Davidson (d. 1861), "Indigestion", 1851 (Reel 1)
    - Bayles, Alfred Hubbard (d. 1871), "Mental Influences as Conductive to Health or Productive of Disease", 1851 (Reel 1)
    - Huntsman, Henry Clay (d. 1887), "The Theory and Treatment of Phlegmasia Dolens", 1851 (Reel 1)
    - Kedzie, Robert Clark (d. 1902), "The Cholera in Kalamazoo", 1851 (Reel 1)
    - O'Brien, John (d. 1868), "The Medulla Oblongata and its Connections", 1851 (Reel 1)
    - Ward, David (d. 1900), "The Young Physician", 1851 (Reel 1)
  - Class of 1852
    - Alden, John Milton (d.1870), "Relation of Anatomy and Physiology to the Sciences", 1852 (Reel 1)
    - Andrews, Edmund (d. 1904), "Final Causes Superior to the Law of Archetypes", 1852 (Reel 1)
    - Brownell, William (d. 1884), "The Pulse and its Modifications", 1852 (Reel 1)
    - Castlehun, Frederick Charles (d. 1905), "Den Rheumatismus", 1852 (Reel 1)
    - Cessna, Benjamin Franklin (d. 1911), "Phthisis", 1852 (Reel 1)
    - Cole, Daniel Harrison (d. 1904), "Animal Heat", 1852 (Reel 1)
    - Cole, James Nelson (d. 1860), "Typhus Fever", 1852 (Reel 1)
    - Collins, William Wadkins (d. 1902), "Carcinoma", 1852 (Reel 1)
    - Cornell, George Lucien (d. 1877), "Opium, its Uses", 1852 (Reel 1)
    - Davis, Roosevelt Hamilton (d. 1905), "Dysentery", 1852 (Reel 1)
    - Eno, Newton Gilbert (d. 1910), "Hygiene", 1852 (Reel 1)
    - Gordon, John Barnum (d. 1858), "Inflammation", 1852 (Reel 1)
    - Hull, Joseph Bowdish (d. 1901), "Structure and Function of the Skin", 1852 (Reel 1)
    - Jamison, John Stearns (d. 1910), "Pericarditis", 1852 (Reel 1)
    - McGee, Edward (d. 1858), "Respiration, the Function and the Means for its Performance", 1852 (Reel 1)
    - Marsh, Charles Pitt (d. ca. 1867), "Quinae Disulphas", 1852 (Reel 1)
    - Mitchell, Dexter Franklin (d. 1892), "Physical Diagnosis and its Application to Pulmonary Diseases", 1852 (Reel 1)
    - Norton, John Cross (d. 1870), "The Chemistry of Therapeutics", 1852 (Reel 1)
    - Paine, Edward Ross (d. 1895), "Epidemic Cholera", 1852 (Reel 1)
    - Ringler, Eugene (d. 1916), "Hernia Inguinalis", 1852 (Reel 1)
    - Stevens, Luman Seely (d. 1899), "Calculi and Calculous Diseases", 1852 (Reel 1)
    - Stevenson, Joseph Hall (d. ca. 1865), "Fever", 1852 (Reel 1)
    - Taylor, Martyn (d. 1906) OR Morse Kent (d. 1889), "The Mutual Dependence and Relation of the Functions", 1852 (Reel 1)
    - Wheeler, John Arthur (d. 1918), "Acute Pneumonia", 1852 (Reel 1)
    - Whitehorn, Samuel (d. 1905), "Of the Vis Nervosa", 1852 (Reel 1)
    - Woodward, Horace Perkins (d. 1901), "Scrofula", 1852 (Reel 1)
  - Class of 1853
    - Arnold, Orrin (d. 1883), "The Value of Ausculation and Percussion", 1853 (Reel 1)
    - Baker, Austin Alonzo (d. 1866), "Pathology and Physical Signs of Tuberculosis Pulmonalis", 1853 (Reel 1)
    - Barross, Franklin Richard (d. 1896), "Neuralgia", 1853 (Reel 1)
    - Bartholomew, Ira Hawley (d. 1889), "The Appetite for and Use of Alcohol", 1853 (Reel 1)
    - Beshoar, Michael (d. 1907), "Cholera Asphyxia", 1853 (Reel 1)
    - Briggs, George Cory (d. 1898), "An Essay on the Relation of Chemistry to the Science of Medicine", 1853 (Reel 1)
    - Bryson, Franklin Towner (d. 1865), "Indigestion", 1853 (Reel 1)
    - Burrows, Sylvester Smith (d. 1906), "Dyspepsia", 1853 (Reel 1)
    - Carpender, George Washington (d. 1903), "Man an Ultimate of Subordinate Beings", 1853 (Reel 1)
    - Carpenter, Benjamin W. (d. 1863), "Lithiasis", 1853 (Reel 2)
    - Carter, George William, "Touch", 1853 (Reel 2)
    - Draper, Edwin Hobart (d. 1900), "Epidemic Cholera", 1853 (Reel 2)
    - Earl, Chauncey (d. 1901), "Pneumenitis", 1853 (Reel 2)
    - Farmer, John Hamilton (d. 1892), "The Ultimate Relation Existing Between Mind and Body as Considered in Regard to Disease", 1853 (Reel 2)
    - Goss, Sanford, "Acute Bronchitis", 1853 (Reel 2)
    - Hall, Oscar Shelding (d. 1902), "Lead Colic", 1853 (Reel 2)
    - Heath, DeLos LeRoy (d. 1903), "Modis Operandi of Medicines", 1853 (Reel 2)
    - Hendrick, Henry Clay (d. 1911), "Gastritis", 1853 (Reel 2)
    - Holley, Dexter Clark (d. 1902), "Relation of Heat to Vital Action", 1853 (Reel 2)
    - Hovey, William Fitch (d. 1907), "Hernia Inguinalis", 1853 (Reel 2)
    - Jennings, Edwin Phillips (d. 1890), "Hysteria", 1853 (Reel 2)
    - Johnson, Joseph Cook (d. 1898), "The History of Medicine", 1853 (Reel 2)
    - Lamb, James (d. 1894), "Indications of Cure", 1853 (Reel 2)
    - Laning, Sylvester (d. 1898), "Scarlatina", 1853 (Reel 2)
    - McChesney, Alfred Brunson (d. 1903), "Ausculation and Percussion", 1853 (Reel 2)
    - Morse, Joel (d. 1866), "Manifestations and Operations of the Law of Mortality", 1853 (Reel 2)
    - Rerick, John Heaton (d. 1911), "Nature and Sequelae of Scarlet Fever", 1853 (Reel 2)
    - Rhodes, Isaac Milton (d. 1897), "The Atmosphere, its Composition and Chemical Relations", 1853 (Reel 2)
    - Roberts, Abel Commins (d. 1901), "Semeiodics of the Respiratory System", 1853 (Reel 2)
    - Slauson, Daniel D. (d. 1878), "Death", 1853 (Reel 2)
    - Smith, Chancellor Hoyt (d. 1857), "Pneumonia", 1853 (Reel 2)
    - Wilkins, David (d. 1905), "The Character and Some of the Duties of the Physician", 1853 (Reel 2)
    - Woodworth, William Motier (d. 1905), "Cells and Cell Life", 1853 (Reel 2)
  - Class of 1854
    - Bailey, John Read (d. 1910), "The Circulation", 1854 (Reel 2)
    - Baker, Charles Thomas (d. 1914), "Rubeola", 1854 (Reel 2)
    - Barnum, Bolivar (d. 1881), "Pathology of the Constituents of the Blood", 1854 (Reel 2)
    - Bates, Orson (d. 1871), "Necrosis", 1854 (Reel 2)
    - Boyce, Nathaniel Stover (d. 1900), "Toxicology of Arsenic", 1854 (Reel 2)
    - Burroughs, Orrin Frank (d. 1906), "Life", 1854 (Reel 2)
    - Chapman, Joseph Miller (d. 1884), "Carcinoma", 1854 (Reel 2)
    - Cole, Samuel Parker, "Chlorosis", 1854 (Reel 2)
    - Derby, Buel Samuel (d. 1892), "Anatomy and Disease of the Iris", 1854 (Reel 2)
    - Dorlund, Elias, "Gestation", 1854 (Reel 2)
    - Ferguson, George (d. 1910), "Vis Vitae", 1854 (Reel 2)
    - Flint, Amos Lawrence (d. 1900), "Respiration", 1854 (Reel 2)
    - Goodno, Isaiah, (d. 1884), "Scarlatina", 1854 (Reel 2)
    - Hall, Daniel (d. 1887), "Animal Heat", 1854 (Reel 2)
    - Herrick, Orson Quincy (d. 1873), "Function of the Liver", 1854 (Reel 2)
    - Howland, Charles Amos (d. 1885), "Hernia", 1854 (Reel 3)
    - King, George Nelson (d. 1854), "Tuberculosis", 1854 (Reel 3)
    - Knight, Philip Atwood (d. 1905), "Atmosphere", 1854 (Reel 3)
    - Leach, Elisha (d. 1910), "Pathology of Acute Peritonitis", 1854 (Reel 3)
    - Marsh, William Richardson (d. 1883), "The Pulse", 1854 (Reel 3)
    - Moody, William Jenning (d. 1895), "Regimental and Medicinal Therapeutics", 1854 (Reel 3)
    - Peak, Orin (d. 1905), "Water as a Therapeutic Agent", 1854 (Reel 3)
    - Peck, William Allen (d. 1875), "Vis Medicatrix Naturae", 1854 (Reel 3)
    - Peebles, John Moody, "Symptoms and Diagnosis of Phthisis Pulmonalis", 1854 (Reel 3)
    - Powell, William Wheeler (d. 1910), "Puerperal Convulsions", 1854 (Reel 3)
    - Randel, Ogden Moses (d. 1895), "Procreation", 1854 (Reel 3)
    - Rice, Oliver Washington (d. 1869), "Epidemic Cholera", 1854 (Reel 3)
    - Robertson, Ewing Welch (d. 1907), "Gun Shot Wounds", 1854 (Reel 3)
    - Rouse, William Henry (d. 1893), "Anaemia", 1854 (Reel 3)
    - Stone, Addison Ray (d. 1888), "Erysipelas", 1854 (Reel 3)
    - Storck, Edward (d. 1897), "Disease, its Course, Duration and Termination", 1854 (Reel 3)
    - Strong, Robert Moncrieff (d. 1891), "Observations on Cerebral Apoplexy", 1854 (Reel 3)
    - Taylor, Edward Chandler, "Puerperal Fever", 1854 (Reel 3)
    - Topping, George Washington (d. 1895), "Predisposing Causes", 1854 (Reel 3)
    - Weller, Fayette Montrose (d. 1895), "Veratrum Veride", 1854 (Reel 3)
    - Westfall, James, "Cacoplastic and Aplastic Deposits", 1854 (Reel 3)
    - Willson, Moses Devoe, "Labor, its Efficient and Determining Causes", 1854 (Reel 3)
    - Winchester, Edgar (d. 1877), "Dislocations", 1854 (Reel 3)
    - Woodard, Isaac (d. 1855), "Modes of Death", 1854 (Reel 3)
    - Yeoman, Stephen Ballard (d. 1865), "Physiology of Digestion", 1854 (Reel 3)
  - Class of 1855
    - Baker, Harvey Scott (d. 1898), "Auscultation", 1855 (Reel 3)
    - Bliss, Zenas Elliott (d. 1877), "Cells and Cell Life", 1855 (Reel 3)
    - Brawn, Addison (d. 1893), "Pneumonia", 1855 (Reel 3)
    - Brown, James Adna (d. 1893), "Physiology of Digestion", 1855 (Reel 3)
    - Brownell, H. H., "Treatment of Puerperal Fever", 1855 (Reel 3)
    - Bullock, William (d. 1893), "Grade of Diseased Action", 1855 (Reel 3)
    - Clements, John Currie (d. 1867), "Erysipelas", 1855 (Reel 3)
    - Corbin, Gilbert Eli (d. 1908), "Oxygen and Carbon and their Relation to Organized Beings", 1855 (Reel 3)
    - Crowell, Reuben (d. 1871), "Acute Pleurisy", 1855 (Reel 3)
    - DuBois, Samuel (d. 1905), "Opium", 1855 (Reel 3)
    - Fanner, Charles P. (d. 1858), "Cataract", 1855 (Reel 3)
    - Fasquelle, Louis William Whiddon (d. 1889), "Acute Peritonitis", 1855 (Reel 3)
    - Greene, William Warren (d. 1862), "Identity of Typhus and Typhoid Fever", 1855 (Reel 3)
    - Hazen, Miner Comstock (d. 1914), "Croup", 1855 (Reel 3)
    - Hendee, Clark Kendrick (d. 1894), "The Reciprocity of Mind and Body", 1855 (Reel 4)
    - Leonard, Charles Willson (d. 1879), "Acute Rheumatism", 1855 (Reel 4)
    - Loop, Joseph Miller (d. 1903), "Dysentery", 1855 (Reel 4)
    - McCurdy, Andrew Taylor, "Etiology of Periodic Fevers", 1855 (Reel 4)
    - Merritt, Charles Austin (d. 1898), "Pneumonia", 1855 (Reel 4)
    - Turner, Horace Crandall (d. 1884), "Erysipelas", 1855 (Reel 4)
    - Woods, Joseph Thatcher (d. 1911), "Homeopathy", 1855 (Reel 4)
  - Class of 1856
    - Baird, John Henry, "The Vaccine Disease", 1856 (Reel 4)
    - Bruce, Thomas Rowland (d. 1914), "Cathartics", 1856 (Reel 4)
    - Charlton, Robert (d. 1865), "Physiological Effects of Alcohol", 1856 (Reel 4)
    - Dean, William Henry (d. 1859), "Gastric Digestion", 1856 (Reel 4)
    - Denison, Frederick C. (d. 1890), "Acute Pneumonia", 1856 (Reel 4)
    - Hershey, Benjamin Jacob (d. 1872), "Syphilitic Bubo", 1856 (Reel 4)
    - Keator, Beers DeVoo (d. 1880), "Vis Vitalis", 1856 (Reel 4)
    - Knapp, Edgar Richard (d. 1910), "The Normal and Abnormal Sounds of the Chest", 1856 (Reel 4)
    - Lansing, Oliver (d. 1876), "The Evidences of Pregnancy", 1856 (Reel 4)
    - Mace, Hiram Green (d. 1901), "Do Medicines Effecting (sic) Nerve Centers, Remote from the Stomach, Enter the Circulation or Act by Simple Contact?", 1856 (Reel 4)
    - May, Henry Clay (d. 1894), "Food and the Digestive Process", 1856 (Reel 4)
    - Merriman, Elisha Smith (d. 1887), "Mental Hygiene and Therapeutics", 1856 (Reel 4)
    - Miller, Charles C. (d. 1920), "Malaria", 1856 (Reel 4)
    - Nash, Alfred (d. 1917), "Diabetes Mellitus", 1856 (Reel 4)
    - Oakley, Francis Marion (d. 1891), "Arsenic", 1856 (Reel 4)
    - Potter, Augustus Owen (d. 1864), "Repair of Fractures", 1856 (Reel 4)
    - Sackrider, Charles H. (d. 1881), "Ether and Chloroform" AND "Extraction of Teeth", 1856 (Reel 4)
    - Seeley, Thaddeus Pomeroy (d. 1898), "The Capillary Power, its Influence on the Circulation of the Blood", 1856 (Reel 4)
    - Spilman, Robert Skelton (d. 1859), "Eclampsia Parturientium", 1856 (Reel 4)
    - Thompson, Almon Alonzo (d. 1892), "Etiology of Apoplexy", 1856 (Reel 4)
    - Turner, John T. (d. 1880), "Psychical Affections, Influence of in Disease and Health", 1856 (Reel 4)
    - Whelan, Arvin Fitzhugh (d. 1890), "Animal Heat", 1856 (Reel 4)
    - White, Ellwood Thomas (d. 1909), "Digestion", 1856 (Reel 4)
    - Whiton, N. Starbuck (d. 1858), "Amenorrhoea", 1856 (Reel 4)
    - Winne, Charles (d. 1912), "Scarlatina", 1856 (Reel 4)
    - Witter, George Franklin (d. 1910), "Quinia", 1856 (Reel 5)
  - Class of 1857
    - Fletcher, Charles Augustus (d. 1887), "Flooding", 1857 (Reel 5)
    - Johnson, Lorenzo M., "Duties of the Attending Accoucheur and Management of Natural Labor" AND "Cod Liver Oil" AND "Peruvian Bark", 1857 (Reel 5)
    - Kay, James Rodger (d. 1892), "Medicine the Mysterious", 1857 (Reel 5)
    - Lilly, Henry Martin (d. 1870), "Relations of the Microscope to the Medical Sciences", 1857 (Reel 5)
    - McFarland, Solomon Fenton (d. 1900), "The Pathology and Treatment of Dyspepsia", 1857 (Reel 5)
    - Merrett, Augustus George, "Necrosis", 1857 (Reel 5)
    - Parmenter, William (d. 1907), "The Oxygen Carriers", 1857 (Reel 5)
    - Redfield, Samuel J. (d. 1863), "Therapeutical Action of Water", 1857 (Reel 5)
    - Rice, John B. (d. 1893), "Sequelae of Malaria", 1857 (Reel 5)
    - Sabin, Samuel Arthur (d. 1871), "Strabismus", 1857 (Reel 5)
    - Sayles, Dwight (d. 1863), "The Evolution of Animal Heat", 1857 (Reel 5)
    - [Smith, Cyrus (d. 1899)], "Auscultation", 1857 (Reel 5)
    - Weeds, James Foulke (d. 1875), "Cholera", 1857 (Reel 5)
    - Wilson, George Byron (d. 1862), "Gangrene and Treatment", 1857 (Reel 5)
    - Woodworth, Milton Case (d. 1897), "Cathartics", 1857 (Reel 5)
  - Class of 1858
    - Anderson, Andrew Lewis (d. 1922), "Anatomy and Treatment of Inguinal Hernia", 1858 (Reel 5)
    - Baird, William Perry (d. 1910), "Nervous Influence and its Relation to Inflammation", 1858 (Reel 5)
    - Bovie, William (d. 1901), "The Dislocation of the Head of the Femur upon the Dorsum Ilii", 1858 (Reel 5)
    - Brown, Ira (d. 1910), "Stricture of the Urethra", 1858 (Reel 5)
    - Chapin, Samuel Farnum (d. 1908), "The Correlation of the Muscular and Nervous Systems", 1858 (Reel 5)
    - Comfort, Jonathan Jones (d. 1906), "Infant Therapeutics", 1858 (Reel 5)
    - Cox, William Geroe, "Etiology of Dropsy", 1858 (Reel 5)
    - Cunynghame, Thurlow, "Properties and Physiological Action of Aconitum Napellus", 1858 (Reel 5)
    - Darling, Horace Madison (d. 1900), "Healthy Facts Physiologically", 1858 (Reel 5)
    - Davis, William Arnold (d. 1915), "Cause of Disease", 1858 (Reel 5)
    - Fisher, William Charles (d. 1879), "The General, Physiological, and Therapeutical Effects of Mercury", 1858 (Reel 5)
    - Hancock, Charles (d. 1919), "Pneumonia", 1858 (Reel 5)
    - Helmer, Albert Miller (d. 1896), "The Cerebrum and its Functions", 1858 (Reel 5)
    - Hosack, Cyrus (d. 1889), "Arsenic as a Poison", 1858 (Reel 5)
    - Leach, Morgan Lewis (d. 1910), "Importance of Hygiene as a Branch of the Healing Art", 1858 (Reel 6)
    - Lord, James Monroe (d. 1869), "The Red Blood Corpuscles", 1858 (Reel 6)
    - Lothrop, Thomas (d. 1902), "Inanition", 1858 (Reel 6)
    - Lyon, William M. (d. 1871), "Inflammation", 1858 (Reel 6)
    - McHench, William Jackson (d. 1910), "Acute Peritonitis" AND "Blood Corpuscles", 1858 (Reel 6)